<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors | Complexity Methods for Behavioural Science</title>
    <link>/authors/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Authors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>/authors/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>admin</title>
      <link>/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert Ford</title>
      <link>/authors/robert-ford/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/robert-ford/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/annab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/annab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;anna-bosman&#34;&gt;Anna Bosman&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hgjj&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/annal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/annal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;anna-lichtwarckaschoff&#34;&gt;Anna Lichtwarck-Aschoff&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/people/anna.png&#34; alt=&#34;AL&#34; style=&#34;float:right;width:100px&#34;/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ru.nl/english/people/lichtwarck-aschoff-a/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was born in the southern part of Germany and moved all the way up to the northern part of the Netherlands to study psychology in Groningen. I received my PhD from the University of Groningen at the department of Developmental Psychology in 2008. Currently, I am working as an assistant professor in the research program Developmental Psychopathology. Generally, I am not so interested in whether certain interventions work but how they work. That is, I am mainly focusing on general processes and mechanisms of change informed by non-linear dynamic systems theories across diagnostic categories and different treatment modalities. Eventually I hope that by understanding individual processes of change we will be able to personalize and tailor treatments to the specific and changing needs of individual clients.
&lt;/br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/fred/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/fred/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;fred-hasselman&#34;&gt;Fred Hasselman&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My research and teaching centers on the development and application of theoretical frameworks and research methods to study of human behaviour, form the perspective of Complexity Science. The main focus is on developing a so-called “person-specific” (idiographic) research paradigm in which modeling and quantification of intra-individual variability (parameters of a complex dynamical system) is more useful than modeling inter-individual variability (estimating parameters of a static population, or true value).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this perspective the current ‘Replicability Crisis’ in the social sciences could be a problem of operating within the wrong theoretical paradigm, rather than the wrong application of research methods and inferential statistics.  &lt;br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;complex-systems-group-at-the-behavioural-science-institute-of-the-radboud-university-nijmegen&#34;&gt;Complex Systems Group at the Behavioural Science Institute of the Radboud University Nijmegen&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ru.nl/bsi/research/group-pages/complex-systems-group/&#34;&gt;https://www.ru.nl/bsi/research/group-pages/complex-systems-group/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/gerrieke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/gerrieke/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;gerrieke-druijfvan-de-woestijne&#34;&gt;Gerrieke Druijf-van de Woestijne&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data Scientist at Neurocast&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teacher at Radboud University Nijmegen  &lt;br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/lisette/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/lisette/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;lisette-de-jongehoekstra&#34;&gt;Lisette de Jonge-Hoekstra&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researcher/teacher Psychology @univgroningen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editor @mw_groningen, starting podcaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Into levels, time scales and perspectives (#mom) of/on child development. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/maarten/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/maarten/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;maarten-wijnants&#34;&gt;Maarten Wijnants&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My research focuses on fractal scaling as it relates to motor coordination and literacy. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hindawi.com/journals/jndy/2014/962043/&#34;&gt;This review paper&lt;/a&gt; provides an excellent summary of my past and current work.     &lt;br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/merlijn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/merlijn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;merlijn-olthof&#34;&gt;Merlijn Olthof&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title of my PhD-project is: “Changing Landscapes: a complex systems approach to psychopathology and intervention”. We use principles from Synergetics, a theory of self-organization in complex systems, to formulate hypotheses about how change in psychopathology occurs. Specifically, we test the hypothesis that abrupt changes in psychopathology (order transitions) are preceded by a period of destabilization, characterized by a temporal increase in disorder called critical fluctuations, and an increased sensitivity to external influences. Early-warning signals indicative for destabilization can be useful for clinical practice, as they signal sensitive periods in which treatment efforts might be more effective.   &lt;br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/ralf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/ralf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;ralf-cox&#34;&gt;Ralf Cox&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ralf Cox is currently associate professor at the Developmental Psychology group of the Department of Psychology of the University of Groningen. He received his PhD in Social Sciences (Cum Laude) at the Radboud University Nijmegen in 2007. He is also adjunct professor at the Center for Research in Human Movement Variability of the University of Nebraska at Omaha (USA) and visiting professor at the Graduate School of Psychology of the Universidad de Talca (Chile).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His research addresses the coordinative basis of behavior, cognition and their development. This entails a micro-genetic and complex dynamical systems approach to intra- and interpersonal coordination, as well as the advancement of nonlinear time-series techniques to study this. He has published on motor performance, planning, language development, dyslexia, mother-child, client-therapist and peer interaction, and gesture-speech attunement.
&lt;/br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
